Menu

Privacy Statement (AU)
======================

_This privacy statement was last changed on January 15, 2024, last checked on January 15, 2024, and applies to citizens of Australia._  

In this privacy statement, we explain what we do with the data we obtain about you via [https://www.forth.com](https://www.forth.com/). We recommend you carefully read this statement. In our processing we comply with the requirements of privacy legislation. That means, among other things, that:

* we clearly state the purposes for which we process personal data. We do this by means of this privacy statement;
* we aim to limit our collection of personal data to only the personal data required for legitimate purposes;
* we first request your explicit consent to process your personal data in cases requiring your consent;
* we take appropriate security measures to protect your personal data and also require this from parties that process personal data on our behalf;
* we respect your right to access your personal data or have it corrected or deleted, at your request.

If you have any questions, or want to know exactly what data we keep of you, please contact us.

On This Page

    * [1.4 To support services or products that a customer wants to buy or has purchased](#14_To_support_services_or_products_that_a_customer_wants_to_buy_or_has_purchased)
    * [1.5 Compiling and analyzing statistics for website improvement.](#15_Compiling_and_analyzing_statistics_for_website_improvement)
* [4\. What if you don't provide us with your personal information?](#4_What_if_you_don039t_provide_us_with_your_personal_information)
* [5\. How we respond to Do Not Track signals & Global Privacy Control](#5_How_we_respond_to_Do_Not_Track_signals_Global_Privacy_Control)

1\. Purpose and categories of data
----------------------------------

We may collect or receive personal information for a number of purposes connected with our business operations which may include the following: (click to expand)

### 1.1 Contact – Through phone, mail, email and/or webforms

The following categories of data are collected

* A first and last name
* An email address
* A telephone number
* IP Address

Retention period

We determine the retention period according to fixed objective criteria: As long as required to service the contacting person and to fulfill record-keeping requirements.

### 1.2 Payments

The following categories of data are collected

* A first and last name
* Account name or alias
* A home or other physical address, including street name and name of a city or town
* An email address
* A telephone number
* IP Address

Retention period

We retain this data until the service is terminated.

### 1.3 Registering an account

The following categories of data are collected

* A first and last name
* Account name or alias
* A home or other physical address, including street name and name of a city or town
* An email address
* A telephone number

Retention period

We retain this data until the service is terminated.

### 1.4 To support services or products that a customer wants to buy or has purchased

The following categories of data are collected

* A first and last name
* Account name or alias
* A home or other physical address, including street name and name of a city or town
* An email address
* A telephone number
* IP Address

Retention period

We retain this data until the service is terminated.

### 1.5 Compiling and analyzing statistics for website improvement.

The following categories of data are collected

* IP Address
* Internet activity information, including, but not limited to, browsing history, search history, and information regarding a consumer's interaction with an Internet Web site, application, or advertisement
* Geolocation data

Retention period

We retain this data until the service is terminated.

2\. Sharing with other parties
------------------------------

We only share or disclose this data to other recipients for the following purposes:

**Purpose of the data transfer:** Gather and analyze statistics related to website usage and visitor behaviors.  
**Country or state in which this processor is located:** USA  
**Purpose of the data transfer:** Credit card processing  
**Country or state in which this processor is located:** United States  

3\. Disclosure practices
------------------------

We disclose personal information if we are required by law or by a court order, in response to a law enforcement agency, to the extent permitted under other provisions of law, to provide information, or for an investigation on a matter related to public safety.

If our website or organisation is taken over, sold, or involved in a merger or acquisition, your details may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchasers and will be passed on to the new owners.

4\. What if you don't provide us with your personal information?
----------------------------------------------------------------

If you don’t provide us with your personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the information, products or assistance that you are seeking.

5\. How we respond to Do Not Track signals & Global Privacy Control
-------------------------------------------------------------------

Our website responds to and supports the Do Not Track (DNT) header request field. If you turn DNT on in your browser, those preferences are communicated to us in the HTTP request header, and we will not track your browsing behavior.

6\. Cookies
-----------

Our website uses cookies. For more information about cookies, please refer to our Cookie Policy on our [Cookie Policy (AU)](https://www.forth.com/cookie-policy-au/) webpage. 

We have concluded a data processing agreement with Google.

The inclusion of full IP addresses is blocked by us.

7\. Security
------------

We are committed to the security of personal data. We take appropriate security measures to limit abuse of and unauthorized access to personal data. This ensures that only the necessary persons have access to your data, that access to the data is protected, and that our security measures are regularly reviewed.

8\. Third party websites
------------------------

This privacy statement does not apply to third party websites connected by links on our website. We cannot guarantee that these third parties handle your personal data in a reliable or secure manner. We recommend you read the privacy statements of these websites prior to making use of these websites.

9\. Amendments to this privacy statement
----------------------------------------

We reserve the right to make amendments to this privacy statement. It is recommended that you consult this privacy statement regularly in order to be aware of any changes. In addition, we will actively inform you wherever possible.

10\. Accessing and modifying your data
--------------------------------------

If you have any questions or want to know which personal data we have about you, please contact us. Please make sure to always clearly state who you are, so that we can be certain that we do not modify or delete any data of the wrong person. We shall provide the requested information only upon receipt of a verifiable consumer request. You can contact us by using the information below. You have the following rights:

10.1 You have the following rights with respect to your personal data

1. You may submit a request for access to the data we process about you.
2. You may request an overview, in a commonly used format, of the data we process about you.
3. You may request correction or deletion of the data if it is incorrect or not or no longer relevant for any purpose under the Privacy Act.

11\. Children
-------------

Our website is not designed to attract children and it is not our intent to collect personal data from children under the age of consent in their country of residence. We therefore request that children under the age of consent do not submit any personal data to us.

12\. Contact details
--------------------

FORTH, Inc.  
6080 Center Drive  
Suite 600  
Los Angeles, CA 90045  
United States  
Website: [https://www.forth.com](https://www.forth.com/)  
Email: support@forth.com  
Toll free phone number: 800-553-6784  
Phone number: 800-553-6784

We have appointed a contact person for the organization’s policies and practices and to whom complaints or inquiries can be forwarded:  
Leon Wagner  
6080 Center Drive, Suite 600, Los Angeles, CA 90045

Annex
-----

### WooCommerce — when you purchase online here

We collect information about you during the checkout process on our store.

What we collect and store
-------------------------

While you visit our site, we’ll track:

* Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed
* Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping
* Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!

We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.

Note: you may want to further detail your cookie policy, and link to that section from here.

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and optional account information like username and password. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:

* Send you information about your account and order
* Respond to your requests, including refunds and complaints
* Process payments and prevent fraud
* Set up your account for our store
* Comply with any legal obligations we have, such as calculating taxes
* Improve our store offerings
* Send you marketing messages, if you choose to receive them

If you create an account, we will store your name, address, email and phone number, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

We generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we will store order information for XXX years for tax and accounting purposes. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.

We will also store comments or reviews, if you choose to leave them.

Who on our team has access
--------------------------

Members of our team have access to the information you provide us. For example, both Administrators and Shop Managers can access:

* Order information like what was purchased, when it was purchased and where it should be sent, and
* Customer information like your name, email address, and billing and shipping information.

Our team members have access to this information to help fulfill orders, process refunds and support you.

What we share with others
-------------------------

In this section you should list who you’re sharing data with, and for what purpose. This could include, but may not be limited to, analytics, marketing, payment gateways, shipping providers, and third party embeds.

We share information with third parties who help us provide our orders and store services to you; for example —

### Payments

In this subsection you should list which third party payment processors you’re using to take payments on your store since these may handle customer data. We’ve included PayPal as an example, but you should remove this if you’re not using PayPal.

We accept payments through PayPal. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to PayPal, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.

Please see the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for more details.

### Shipment Tracking

For products that are shipped physically, the destination address and other information may be retained indefinitely.

### Complianz | The Privacy Suite for WordPress

This website uses the Privacy Suite for WordPress from Complianz to collect records of consent. For this functionality your IP address is anonymized and stored in our database. For more information, see the Complianz [Privacy Statement](https://complianz.io/privacy-statement/).

Search for:  

SwiftForth
----------

**Interactive Development Environment**  
SwiftForth brings the fast, powerful, ANS Forth programming language to Windows, Linux, and macOS.  

SwiftX
------

**Forth Cross Compilers**  
Interactive hosted development environment for embedded systems on a wide range of microcontrollers and microprocessors.  

**Forth Books by the experts.**

_Forth Application Techniques_ helps you learn practical Forth programming from basic to advanced.

_Forth Programmer's Handbook_ has earned its reputation as the de facto Standard Forth reference manual, no matter which Forth implementation you use.

The classics _Starting FORTH_ and _Thinking FORTH_ are both available online.

Starting FORTH
--------------

Free Bonus
----------

Brodie fans can get his _Thinking Forth_ free at the [Forth books](https://www.forth.com/resources/forth-books/) page.

Copyright © 2024 FORTH, Inc. | [Web development services by External Design](https://www.externaldesign.com/)  
[privacy](https://www.forth.com/privacy-statement/?cmplz_region_redirect=true/) • [cookies](https://www.forth.com/cookie-policy?cmplz_region_redirect=true/&cmplz-region=us/) • [terms](https://www.forth.com/terms-conditions/) • [impressum](https://www.forth.com/impressum/)

Manage Cookie Consent

We use cookies to optimize our website and our service.

Functional  Functional Always active

The technical storage or access is strictly necessary for the legitimate purpose of enabling the use of a specific service explicitly requested by the subscriber or user, or for the sole purpose of carrying out the transmission of a communication over an electronic communications network.

Preferences  Preferences

The technical storage or access is necessary for the legitimate purpose of storing preferences that are not requested by the subscriber or user.

Statistics  Statistics

The technical storage or access that is used exclusively for statistical purposes. The technical storage or access that is used exclusively for anonymous statistical purposes. Without a subpoena, voluntary compliance on the part of your Internet Service Provider, or additional records from a third party, information stored or retrieved for this purpose alone cannot usually be used to identify you.

Marketing  Marketing

The technical storage or access is required to create user profiles to send advertising, or to track the user on a website or across several websites for similar marketing purposes.

Accept Deny Preferences Save preferences [Preferences](#)

Manage Cookie Consent

Cookies help optimize this website and its services.

Functional  Functional Always active

The technical storage or access is strictly necessary for the legitimate purpose of enabling the use of a specific service explicitly requested by the subscriber or user, or for the sole purpose of carrying out the transmission of a communication over an electronic communications network.

Preferences  Preferences

The technical storage or access is necessary for the legitimate purpose of storing preferences that are not requested by the subscriber or user.

Statistics  Statistics

The technical storage or access that is used exclusively for statistical purposes. The technical storage or access that is used exclusively for anonymous statistical purposes. Without a subpoena, voluntary compliance on the part of your Internet Service Provider, or additional records from a third party, information stored or retrieved for this purpose alone cannot usually be used to identify you.

Marketing  Marketing

The technical storage or access is required to create user profiles to send advertising, or to track the user on a website or across several websites for similar marketing purposes.

Accept Deny Preferences Save preferences [Preferences](#)

Manage consent Manage consent
